Diane, earlier this lesson you mentioned learning effects.
Diane 你曾在这节课的早些时候提到了学习效应
Can we talk about those some more?
你现在可以详细说说吗？
First remind me what they are?
首先请讲解一下这是什么意思？
>> Sure.
好的
So learning effects is basically when you want to measure user learning.
学习效应就是指衡量用户的学习情况
Or effectively whether a user is adapting to a change or not.
或者用户是否适应一项更改
Now we had briefly mentioned these back in lesson one where we talked about
我们曾在第一课中简要提及了
two different types of learning effects.
两种类型的学习效应
Change aversion, where when users first see a change they're like, what is this?
更改版本 当用户第一次看到版本更改时 他们可能会感到惊讶 这是什么东西？
I don't like anything.
我一点也不喜欢！
Or a novelty effect which is the exact opposite.
相反 他们也可能产生新奇效应
Oh, this is a new thing.
哟 有新版本了
What's going on?
有什么新功能？
Let me try everything around.
我来试试看
Now, in both situations, what happens is that when a user first sees a change,
在这两种情况中 当用户第一次看到更改时
they're going to tend to react in one of these two ways.
他们都会做出这两种反应之一
But over time they're going to probably plateau to a very different behavior.
但是一段时间之后 他们都可能做出不同的行为
Now, the key issue with trying to measure a learning effect is time.
衡量学习效应的关键问题在于时间
It takes time for you just to actually adapt to a change and often times
用户需要花时间来适应更改
you don't have the luxury of taking that much time to make a decision.
但你通常没有那么多时间来做决策
>> Okay, but if you do have that much time to spend,
如果我的时间很充裕的话
is there anything to keep in mind?
有什么需要注意的？
>> Sure, there's a bunch of things to keep in mind.
需要注意的事项很多
Now one of them I mentioned earlier in this lesson which is choosing the unit
在这节课早些时候
of diversion correctly.
我曾提到需要正确选择分组单元
If you want to measure user learning,
衡量学习效应时
you need a stateful unit of diversion like a cookie or a user ID.
你需要使用有状态的分组单元 例如 cookie 或用户 ID
The second issue that we want to take into account is that
第二个注意事项是
because a lot of the learning is based on not just a slight time but
因为学习效应不仅取决于时间
how often they see the change so we call that a dosage.
还取决于用户看到更改的周期 我们称之为频率
Then you probably want to be using a cohort as opposed to just a population.
然后 你可能希望使用队列而不是总体
And so you would choose a cohort in both the experiment and
那么你可能会选择根据用户看到更改的时间或次数
the control based on either how long they've been exposed to the change or
为实验组和对照组
how many times they've seen it.
选择队列
Now the last issue is a question about both the risk and duration.
最后一点是风险和持续时间的问题
Right?
对吧？
From a duration perspective,
就持续时间而言
because you want to measure a learning effect, this is going to take
因为你要衡量学习效应
some amount of time to basically see what's going to be happening.
这需要花费一定时间才能看到结果
Now, the other thing though, is that it's going to take a long,
这个时间可能会
a long period of time.
很长很长
You don't want to be putting a lot of your users
当某项更改的测试持续时间很长时
through a change that you're testing over a long period of time because
你可能不希望让太多用户受到影响
maybe you end up testing other changes.
因为最后你可能转而测试其他更改
Now, the other thing is one about risk.
另一点是风险
If you're actually wanting to measure a user learning effect, that means that
在衡量用户的学习效应时
you're probably a little uncertain about what the effect is going to be,
你可能不太确定这个效应到底是怎样的
which means that it's probably a higher risk change.
也就是说 更改的风险可能较高
Now, both of those mean that you're probably going to want to run it
基于这两个方面 你可能会想针对较少比例的用户
through a small proportion of your users for a longer period of time.
开展一项持续时间较长的实验
>> That makes sense, and is there anything else you would do?
这很有道理 你还可能做些什么？
>> Well, we've done a lot at Google,
在 Google
because we've done a lot of looking at sort of user learning.
因为我们对用户的学习效应有过深入研究
Is that we've developed methodology where we use both pre-periods and
所以我们使用前期和后期理论来开发
post-periods.
方法
Now, both pre-periods and post-periods are, those uniformity trials.
前期和后期都涉及一致性试验
There's a versus a test that we discussed back in lesson three.
我们曾在第三课中提到 A/A 测试
But what we're doing is instead of using it across the entire system,
我们不会在整个系统中都使用它
we're using it in a way that's specific to your experiment and your control.
我们会根据实验组和对照组的具体情况来进行选择
And so what happens is that before you run your A/B test on your
在针对某个总体对实验组和对照组进行 A/B 测试之前
experimental control, and you have those populations, you're on a pre-period on
你处于前期阶段
the exact same populations but they're receiving the exact same frequence.
总体没有变化 但用户看到更改的频率完全相同
It's an A versus A test on the same set of users.
这是对相同的用户集进行 A/A 测试
And what happens in the pre-period is that if you measure any difference
在前期 如果你衡量到
between your experiment and
实验组和对照组的总体存在差异
your control populations that difference is due to something else.
那么这些差异应该是源于其他因素
Maybe system variability, user variability, things like that.
例如系统差异性和用户差异性之类的
Now a pre-period I would note, is useful not just for
强调一下
when you want to test user learning, but sort of across the board.
前期不仅在你要测试用户学习效应时很实用 而且在所有情况下都很实用
So that you know that any difference that you measure in your experiment and
从而 你在实验中衡量到的任何差异
control is due to the experiment, and
都源自实验本身
not due to any preexisting and inherent differences in your population.
而不是总体中事先存在的固有差异
Now, that's what a pre-period is, and that basically says, okay,
这就是前期 它基本上相当于说
I don't have any differences in my populations.
总体中没有任何差异
A post-period is saying, after I run my experiment,
后期是指 在针对实验组和对照组开展实验之后
my control, I'm going to run another A versus A test.
我还准备进行另一个 A/A 测试
And then, what,
此时
what we can say is that if there are any differences in the experiment and
在实验完成之后
the control populations after I've run my experiment, then I can attribute
如果在实验组和对照组的总体中衡量到任何差异
those differences to user learning that happened in the experiment period.
我就可以认为其源自实验周期中产生的用户学习效应
And so, that's what we basically do.
我们做的就是这些
Now, the key thing that I sort of note is that
我想强调的重要问题是
these are pretty advanced techniques.
这些是高级技巧
If you're really trying to measure user learning, hopefully you've run tens,
如果你曾开展过成百上千次实验
if not, hundreds of experiments already.
那么你可以利用这些技巧来衡量用户学习效应
If not, I'd probably stick to some of the simpler techniques.
否则我建议你还是使用那些初级技巧